23i
people offering food okay and it's a big
custom in my the people who translated
the food press they asked me what's this
word grace okay
in English we say grace and grace has
three meanings okay
one is the person moves with grace like
when they walk did they almost look like
they are dancing okay that's called
grace in English this person is very
graceful okay
the second meaning of grace is blessing
of the Lama or blessing of God God's
grace and then the third meaning of
grace means before you eat before you
drink you you offer to buna first okay
all right okay to the three jewels you
offer so this is a refuge from what
number is number eight okay you should
offer the first part of anything you eat
or drink okay and what's the emergency
prayer yeah like no like this okay like
the last home it's also sick okay but
you know you should get in the whammer's
offering always okay
and like all religious things it becomes
a bad habit you know you're like oh ho
like you don't think about it anymore
that's a danger for all of us you don't
think about it Sachi producing music
engaging delete data buggy
Doku non-nursing larger parcel so try to
not get in a bad you know like take some
take a moment we're very very busy all
of us are busy i'm dharma busy me and
it's gotten only route dharma busy we're
doing dharma all over the world all the
time and sometimes you don't have time
to think about you know you know try to
pause and because we like to eat three
or four or five ten times a day we can
get three or four five or ten chances to
pause and connect with our refuge okay
with the with the three jewels okay so
learn to do this you can practice in the
tree cuz you're not busy okay two days
we can spend three minutes go to the end
of the book take the prayer you like the
grace okay it doesn't have to be a
christian word okay can be a buddhist
foreign british grace and and pick the
one okay first one three draws by the
way that yeah okay
the Tibetans also here if you want to
learn it the pronunciation is here but I
would say do it in your own language
okay second one is a grace for your
teachers if you're feeling like you want
to make an offering to your teacher of
ding dong or cupcake hostess cupcake
subsidy whatever bad for your having
okay so in words it's a great if you
want to improve your meditation okay so
that would be a good one to do during
the tree because you're offering good
meditation to other people okay first
one is the grace if you have food
problems like me like you can't
eating cakes or okay if you have food
problems be number four my god you miss
grace okay nice if you can't stop
yourself from eating or eat too much or
you eat bad things you know ask for help
this grace number four says I don't want
to eat to be beautiful or I don't want
to eat to be strong and someone asked me
a good question which I won't repeat
they said get on your said you taught
many times the best teacher is someone
who is a good example you see like the
best way to teach is to follow what you
say right if you're obviously following
what you say people will respect you and
listen to what you're teaching okay so
they said I like to eat carefully so my
body looks beautiful so people who are
just starting Buddhism will be attracted
to me and that's a good motivation okay
that's okay
I bought a suit I bought a Bulgarian
mafia suit because it looks cool you
know somebody told me when I tell you
the under grace and I said yeah that's
what I'm trying to do you know and the
point issues you know I always wanted
you know actually a Bulgarian Muffy that
bought it for me so you know that's okay
that's not pride that's I want to look
nice because I want more people to come
to class and so that's okay that kind of
motivation is not what we're talking
about here you know this is a bad
motivation you know I want to look
beautiful so I get more attention or -
my boyfriend likes me more is something
like that okay more boys like me okay
number five and the fifth grace is
if you want to connect with some copper
which means if you want to understand
what the Buddha said okay if you want to
understand what the Buddha said there's
nothing better than some companies
nothing ever never
okay all right
and the last grace is very very
beautiful very very powerful grace -
attempting angel okay bud you give me to
God you jumble
so that's that's a beautiful one and in
that one it's nice to do it retreat
your pretend you are her you eat the
food you offer the food to her directly
okay like this okay ready I'm gonna do
number six
I'm budgeted Unni I'm gonna offer this
to you thanks I got it
it's very cool it's a little
schizophrenia okay I'm gonna and I'm
offering to do it
okay and it's very powerful it's a very
good custom okay all right what happened
that's good enough to drink cappuccinos
no they don't need food they don't need
water they're not living on food or
water okay
they don't need to drink it what happens
to a Buddha when they drink cappuccino
they don't get nervous they don't get
alert taste the emptiness again but
didn't I see em do this before they had
the cup of milk yes they saw emptiness
here here
but when we offer food to Buddha we're
supposed to imagine when it touch their
lives they get more emptiness like wow
and they feel super cool you know
like super cappuccino emptiness
cappuccino wow that's good
you know and they become vision is even
deeper okay got it
and and it makes them super happy so we
call emptiness and bliss okay we have
emptiness in bliss okay got it
so that's number six that's good number
six you have time during a retreat to
take your time to do your Grace's so do
it and learn them okay pick one that you
want meditation you want
Biagio Guinea when you want you choose
it okay and and memorize it good to know
it okay if you say it for ten days it'll
come automatically you will start to
learn it okay and that's that's
wonderful to have that in your Dharma
toolkit okay all right